theidm.com 2014-06-28

# The legal stuff: privacy, policies, security and copyright

The following explains how we collect, store and use your personal data and data about you when you visit this or our other websites and when you transact with us. It also describes the types of data we collect, how we use this data to ensure we provide relevant and timely services to you, and your rights to control our use of that data.

By visiting this or our other websites and in providing any data about yourself to us, you are confirming that you have read, understood and agree to our policies and practices. If you are at all uncertain about any aspect of our policies and practices, please contact us and refrain from using this and our other websites.

 **The IDM respects your privacy and safeguards your data.**

 **The personal data we collect, process or use is treated securely and in accordance with the IDM's privacy policy, described below. Whenever you give us personal data, you are consenting to its collection and use in accordance with this policy, including our use of cookies explained below.**

### What personal data do we collect?

You will be asked for personal data such as your name, address and email address when you register, join as a member, make an enquiry or order products and services from us..

### How do we use your personal data?

Where appropriate, we use your personal data:

  * to provide goods and services to you or your organisation
  * for basic profiling purposes
  * to let you know about other goods and services in which you may be interested
  * to inform you about changes and improvements to this website

If you register or enrol you will receive email communications alerting you to news and offers. You may choose not to receive these.

### Transfer of data

By the nature of the Internet, the personal data you supply through this website may be sent electronically to servers anywhere in the world. It may be used, stored and processed anywhere in the world, including countries outside the European Economic Area. Bear in mind that many countries outside the EEA do not adequately protect your rights as a data subject.

### To whom might we disclose your personal data?

The IDM does not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others. Your details will be added to the IDM database in order to process your request, and so that you can be kept up to date with relevant details of our education, training, information and membership services. From time to time the IDM holds joint events with selected partners. If you book to attend one of these events your details will be made available to the event partner. You will be advised of this at the time of booking, to opt-out of receiving any communications from the IDM and/or the event partner, please [notify us](mailto:macs@theidm.com).

Your personal data may be required to be passed to a third party if they need it in order to fulfil your order(s) for our goods and services, or to execute the communications we send to you. Except as set out above, we shall not disclose your personal information unless obliged to, or allowed to do so by law, or where we need to in order to run our business (e.g. where other people process data for us). In such circumstances, we ask those people to give us confidentiality or non-disclosure undertakings.

### Marketing messages

You may at any time request us to stop using your personal data for marketing purposes. To do so, contact [servicesteam@theidm.com](mailto:servicesteam@theidm.com).

### Links

This site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these and you should read their own privacy policies. The policy described here, applies only to personal data collected by the IDM.

### Security

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet is guaranteed 100% secure, but we do take appropriate steps to protect the security of your personal data.

### Inaccuracies and corrections

We endeavour to keep your personal data accurate and up to date. If you become aware of errors or inaccuracies, please email [servicesteam@theidm.com](mailto:servicesteam@theidm.com).

### Changes to this policy

The IDM privacy policy may change at any time, so you may wish to check it each time you visit our website.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent from our web server to your browser. It is stored on your hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites, and will not damage your system. If you would like to know more about cookies please visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### How do we use cookies on theidm.com?

The IDM use cookies to show us which areas of the site are popular and those that are not often visited, thus enabling us to use our website resources in the most effective way.  We do not use them to identify you.

We use session cookies to keep you logged in for the duration of your visit, to enable you to complete transactions on this website and, for example, to pre-populate forms with information to save you keying in data that you have already provided.

We use permanent cookies to record basic web traffic analysis using Google Analytics and to remember you on your return to theidm.com, but only if you have ticked the 'Remember me' facility on logging in.

### Email communications

The IDM uses cookies in its email communications to track whether that communication has been opened and read, and whether the recipient has used the onward links contained in the email. This allows us to monitor and improve our email communications.

### What we do not use cookies for

IDM cookies do not analyse visits to other website or any searches undertaken whilst on the IDM website. We do not use cookies for any third-party activities (other than Google Analytics as described above), or to insert any contextual advertising.

### How can you manage the use of cookies on this website?

You can reset your browser to refuse cookies or alert you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept cookies, some features of this site might not work as intended (e.g. services accessed while logged in, and all transaction/checkout facilities). We do not use cookies to identify you personally, except when you opt to use the 'Remember me' facility on logging in.

You can find out further information at:

  * <http://www.google.com/chrome/intl/en/more/privacy.html>
  * <http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Cookies#w_cookie-settings>
  * <http://windows.microsoft.com/en-US/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies>
  * <http://www.apple.com/safari/features.html#security>

 **Keeping your financial information secure: rest assured that any credit or debit card details you provide will be processed, transmitted and stored with the utmost care and security.**

### SecureTrading

All credit and debit card payments made on this website are processed by SecureTrading, a carefully chosen payment service provider. The IDM does not store your card details on this site—this information is held only on a well-protected SecureTrading enterprise server, and all transactions are encrypted between your browser and the server. No personal or financial details are left unencrypted on a remote server, and such details are never sent by email.

Of equal importance is the security surrounding the payment system itself. Our partnership with SecureTrading allows the IDM to safely process your card payment through your bank, and to complete the transaction securely behind protected firewalls.

SecureTrading is a subscribing member to the VeriSign Secure Site programme. This gives you further assurance that:

  * VeriSign has verified the organisational name;
  * the site legitimately runs under the auspices of VeriSign;
  * all information sent to the site is encrypted if in an SSL (Secure Socket Layer) session, protecting against disclosure to third parties.

Elsewhere on the IDM website, SSL encryption is used wherever we ask you to supply payment details.

### "How will I know I'm in a secure page on this website?"

You can check if you are in a secure part of any website by looking for the 'closed padlock' symbol. (usually found in the bottom-right corner of the screen in your browser's task bar). Double-click on the padlock for details of the site's security certification. Also, when in secure areas, the address bar at the top of the browser shows the prefix 'https' (rather than just 'http').

 **The IDM logo and contents of this website (including text, design and graphics) are trademarked and copyrighted materials of either the IDM or its partners. All rights are reserved.**

### Downloading documents and files

Permission is given to users of this website for the downloading and temporary storage of pages where indicated, for the sole purpose of individual viewing on a standalone PC or monitor. Such pages may be printed, but these may not be further reproduced, copied or transmitted in any way to those other than the initial user.

All other use, reproduction, downloading or storage without prior consent from the IDM, of any copyright or proprietary materials available on this site in any manner, is strictly prohibited.

### Our trademark

IDM and its logo are registered trademarks in a number of countries. These may be used, transmitted and reproduced only in accordance with instructions issued by the IDM. No other use, transmission or reproduction is permitted.

 **The Institute is a member of the Marketing and Sustainability Steering Group in the UK.**

Environmental issues, including sustainable marketing practice, are some of the most pressing issues facing society. The IDM recognises the need for sustainable development and consumption, and is committed to improving the environmental impact of its activities.

The Institute is committed to continually improving its environmental performance, particularly in the areas set out below. We aim to achieve this by working with our members, customers, suppliers and through training and educating our employees. We shall monitor and regularly review the progress we are making with the programme of environmental initiatives that include, but are not limited to:

### Membership Cards

In 2009, the IDM transferred to environmentally-friendly membership cards. These cards are made by [oomph!™](http://www.madebyoomph.co.uk/), and are created from recycled credit cards. They can be readily recycled again. (IDM members signing up for their "Fantastic with Plastic" loyalty scheme will also earn double points.)

### Energy and water

We have implemented a number of efficiency measures to reduce our consumption of energy and water.

### Recycling

The IDM participates in the London Borough of Richmond’s _Business Recycling Programme_. The majority of our office waste is recycled through this scheme, and we are actively assessing other ways of recycling the waste that is not covered by the Borough’s programme.

### Print and paper

We have significantly reduced our use of paper through a number of measures. Recycled paper and office products are used wherever possible.

IDM promotional materials (brochures, leaflets, etc.) are printed on paper from sustainable forests and are elemental chlorine free.

### Course delegates

Some 2,000 training delegates and qualifications candidates pass through the IDM’s training suites each year. We provide recycling facilities for the use of delegates and, where possible, we offer the option to receive training manuals by CD-ROM rather than on paper.

We also source fair-trade refreshments for our delegates where possible.

### Suppliers

We take into account environmental policies when selecting suppliers, particularly those related to print, marketing services and office facilities.

### Transport

The IDM is a member of the Cycle to Work Scheme. We are also assessing a number of other ideas that will support and encourage our staff to travel to work and meetings using public transport. We encourage delegates to use public transport when they travel to our courses and events.

#### Working with other marketers

The Institute is represented on the UK’s _**Marketing and Sustainability Steering Group**_ , whose objective is "to create measurable engagement by marketers, communicators and sales personnel in support of sustainable (responsible) marketing practices."

 *****PAS 2020*****  
Find out more [online](http://www.bsigroup.com/en/About-BSI/News-Room/BSI-News-Content/Disciplines/Sustainability/PAS-2020-publication/) about the January 2009 environmental initiative which has been developed by BSI British Standards, in association with the Direct Marketing Association (DMA).

If you’d like to offer any ideas on how the IDM might further reduce its environmental impact and make its working practices more sustainable, please email [enquiries@theidm.com](mailto:enquiries@theidm.com). Thank you.

 **Material and software available on this website, and in linked sites directly or indirectly accessible from this site, are provided on an 'as is' basis, with no warranty of any kind, express or implied, including those of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose.**

### Important disclaimer notice

The IDM does not guarantee that any software available on or via this site is virus-free, without defects, Year 2000-compliant, compatible with other software or operating systems or suitable for any specific purpose. The IDM accepts no liability for any loss or damage of whatsoever nature caused by the downloading, installation or use of any such software.

Any references to linked sites or to third-party companies, products or services by name does not constitute or infer their endorsement by the Institute.

The IDM has used all reasonable endeavours to ensure that information provided through this site is accurate at the time of inclusion; however, it accepts no liability for any inaccuracies, errors or omissions on the site. The information available on the site might be incomplete, out of date or inaccurate. The IDM reserves the right at any time and without prior notice to make changes and corrections to the material on the site.

The IDM accepts no liability for any loss or damage of whatsoever nature caused by the use or the inability to use the materials available on this site or any linked site.

The IDM has taken all reasonable steps to ensure that the intellectual property of third parties is not infringed. If, however, you genuinely believe that the material on this site infringes any intellectual property rights, please email [servicesteam@theidm.com](mailto:servicesteam@theidm.com?CC=backup@theidm.com&Subject=Privacy%2C%20security%20and%20copyright%20%28enquiry%20from%20IDM%20website%29).
